KEIVER HERNANDEZ FERNANDEZ

Senior Web Developer

1536 SW 9th St, Apt 1 Miami, FL 33135 +1 786 478 1546 kiverh@gmail.com

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Passionate IT professional with over 6 years of experience designing and programming web and desktop applications, with a strong background in Agile and Test-Driven Development.

Specialized in frontend development with solid knowledge of JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, AngularJS, JQuery and User Experience Design as well as comprehensive experience in backend development of API and RESTful services; with know-how of open source tools to develop on GNU/Linux environments.

TOOLS AND TECHNOLOGIES

	Programming Languages	PHP, JavaScript , C/C++, C#, VB.Net, ASP.NET, HTML5, CSS3, XML, JSON, SASS, LESS
	Version Control	Git, SVN, GitHub, JIRA, RedMine
	Database Management	MySQL/MariaDB, MongoDb, MSSQL Server, Sphinx Server, PostgreSQL
	Libraries and Frameworks	Bootstrap, JQuery, Angular JS, Ionic, Yii2, Codelgniter, .NET, Qt Framework
	Operating Systems	Windows 7/8/10, Windows Server, RedHat, Ubuntu GNU/Linux, OS X
	Areas of Expertise	Web Development, Mobile Development, ERP Customization, Data Analysis, GUI Design, Web Responsive Design, SEO, TDD, User Experience, Software Accessibility, SaaS

EDUCATION

Postgraduate Studies on Teaching and Innovation — University of Computer Sciences, Havana, Cuba (2010 - 2013)

Bachelor of Computer Science — University of Computer Sciences, Havana, Cuba (2004 - 2009)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Web Developer • August 2015 – Present Day Teqspring Inc., Las Vegas, Nevada, USA

Responsibilities:

Full-stack programmer of web applications.

- ✓ Designed and put into practice several mechanisms and patterns to clean and identify useful data
- ✓ Improved parsing functionalities, increasing the quality of the information in more than 80%.
- ✓ Integrated latest version of APIs to comply with the core business of the application
- ✓ Increased consumer experience with the development of an online purchase catalog

Technologies: PHP, PCRE, MariaDB, Git, GitHub, HML5, CSS3, JSON, Sphinx Server, JQuery, Twitter Bootstrap, Yii2

Senior Web/ERP Developer • November 2014 – July 2015 Numencorp SA, Quito, Ecuador

Responsibilities:

Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) systems developer and designer.

- ✓ Increased management potential for customers by developing new customized modules for an ERP system
- ✓ Improved customer experience by optimizing how the application handled large volumes of data
- ✓ Handled critical issues for already-on-production ERP application instances

Technologies: AngularJS, PHP, PECL, PEAR, MySQL, Git, HML5, CSS3, XML, JSON, JavaScript, JQuery, Twitter Bootstrap

Web Developer • July 2013 – October 2014 Northern Exposed Inc., Toronto, Canada

Responsibilities:

Assisting in the design, coding, and testing of web applications, as well as migrating old websites to newer technologies.

- ✓ Assessed technologies migration for already-in-production web applications
- ✓ Enhanced graphic user interfaces and user experience, adapting sites to be responsive to different devices
- ✓ Improved customer support by developing an intern application to manage change requests
- ✓ Increased clients revenue with the development of e-commerce sites
- ✓ Decreased server failure times and improved database structure and maintenance

Technologies: Twitter Bootstrap, AngularJS, ASP.NET, VBScript, MS SQL Server, Git, HML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery

Desktop Application Developer/Project Leader • September 2009 – June 2013 ALBET SA, Havana, Cuba

Responsibilities:

Leading the development team for an application to create and clone ISO images of GNU/Linux operating systems.

- ✓ Managed the software requirements and team resources
- ✓ Evaluated architectural changes and integration issues with Nova GNU/Linux
- ✓ Simplified graphical user interfaces and their behavior

Technologies: C/C++, Qt Framework, QtCreator, Bash, PHP, Linux Kernel, Grub, SVN, RedMine

CERTIFICATIONS

Scrum Master Accredited Certification - Certificate Id: 44385580153670, http://www.scrum-institute.org/, 2015

Scrum Certification For Web Developer - Certificate Id: 32363845809362, http://www.scrum-institute.org/, 2016

Scrum Certification For Mobile App Developer - Certificate Id: 37966506729833, http://www.scrum-institute.org/, 2016